Christopher Adekunle

Asokoro, Abuja | (234) 703-567-8126 | christopher.adekunle@outlook.com | christopheradekunle.netlify.app

Summary

Focused and quick-learning Software Engineer with over 3 years experience in commercial application and software development using HTML/CSS, JavaScript(ReactJS, NextJS React Native, Redux, Expo, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB), PHP(Laravel), Git, Github, MySQL, AWS for various projects.

Education

Ecole Professionelle Specialiseé La-Cité Université

Sept 2016 - Oct 2020

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science GPA 4.5 / 5.0

Certificates

- Certified Front End Development Libraries, Freecodecamp
- Certified Back End Development Libraries and APIs, Freecodecamp
- Certified Data Visualization, Freecodecamp
- Certified JavaScript Data Structure and Algorithm, Freecodecamp
- Certificate of Achievement, Accelerated Jobberman Soft Skills Training

Work Experience

Matrix Point Technology

Software Engineer

Garki, Abuja June 2022 – Dec 2022

- Worked on EIA application using PHP Laravel MVC for the Federal Ministry of Environment routine assessment
- Designed web application interfaces using Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS with BEM naming convention for professionalism
- Designed databases model using Laravel Eloquent for various client's application
- Integrate code changes, test code changes and document code changes

Army Headquarters Garrison

Asokoro, Abuja

National Youth Service Corp, Abuja, IT Assistant

May 2021 – May 2022

- Taught Army Personnel utilization of Microsoft Office Suite boosting productivity by 6%
- Worked with Microsoft Excel for calculating inventory at the Army Headquarters Garrison
- Created PowerPoint Presentations for Army Officers during conferences

Freelancer

Software Engineer

Sept 2018 - May 2022

- Worked on web application projects for clients such blog site, e-commerce, business sites and so on using HTML/CSS, PHP Codeigniter framework.
- Designed portfolio projects using NodeJS, React, NextJS, JQuery, MongoDB with great functionality.
- Created modern and beautiful UI/UX using Bootstrap and Tailwind CSS

- Designed Databases from relational to object-oriented using MYSQL and MongoDB respectively for back-end applications
- Created and deployed web pages with HTML, JavaScript and CSS

Projects

Raja Listing App

- Created an ecommerce listing app using React Native, Expo, Express, MongoDB, Cloudinary, Redux e.t.c
- Designed reusable user component on the application
- Created a backend server for the application hosted on Render web hosting
- Integrated code changes, test code changes and document code changes
- Published the app to the Expo Store for access anywhere around the world

GPT UX Site

- Created an SPA with great UI/UX experience
- Created the SPA using React Js, JSX and CSS.
- Designed mobile responsiveness for the application.

Skills

- JavaScript(ES6, ReactJS, React Native, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB)
- HTML/CSS (Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS)
- PHP (Laravel, MYSQL)
- AWS (S3 Bucket, I AM, EC3, Mail Service)
- Operating System(Linux, Window)
- Adaptability
- Interpersonal Communication Skills
- Teamwork

Languages

- English (Fluent)
- French (Conversational)